Preliminary Guide to the Mount Vernon Seminary and College Nebraska Avenue Campus collection, 1917-1942 MVC0003
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Mount Vernon Seminary and College Nebraska Avenue Campus Collection
1917-1942
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Mount Vernon College
Mount Vernon Seminary
MVC0003
12 Linear Feet
Having outgrown its M Street location, Mount Vernon Seminary moved to a 15.5-acre campus on Nebraska Avenue, NW, in 1917. School founder Elizabeth J. Somers died in 1924, and the Elizabeth Somers Chapel was dedicated on campus in 1925. Adelia Gates Hensley was headmistress until her death in 1923, when Jean Dean Cole became headmistress, a position she held until her death in 1939. It was under Ms. Cole's administration that MVS was divided into the preparatory and Junior College divisions. MVS celebrated the 50th anniversary of the seminary with a Golden Jubilee in 1925, and celebrated the Centenary in 1937 in observance of the 100th birthday of Mrs. Somers. In 1942, the United States Navy took over the Nebraska Avenue campus to use its facilities for the war effort.
Biographical / Historical
Having outgrown its M Street location, Mount Vernon Seminary moved to a 15.5-acre campus on Nebraska Avenue, NW, in 1917. The buildings and layout of the campus were designed by New York architect Wesley S. Bessell and the campus was formally dedicated on November 5, 1917, Mrs. Somers' 80th birthday. Mrs. Somers died in 1924, and the Elizabeth Somers Chapel was dedicated on campus in 1925. Adelia Gates Hensley was headmistress until her death in 1923, when Jean Dean Cole became headmistress, a position she held until her death in 1939. It was under Ms. Cole's administration that MVS was divided into the preparatory and Junior College divisions. MVS celebrated the 50th anniversary of the seminary with a Golden Jubilee in 1925, and celebrated the Centenary in 1937 in observance of the 100th birthday of Mrs. Somers. In 1942, the United States Navy took over the Nebraska Avenue campus to use its facilities for the war effort. The complex is now home to the Department of Homeland Security.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains photographs, lantern slides, scrapbooks, programs, articles, menus, correspondence, and artifacts documenting the Mount Vernon Seminary and College students, faculty, and campus during the years 1917 through 1942, when the campus was located on Nebraska Avenue.
Arrangement
Organized into four series: Images, Scrapbooks, Ephemera and documents, and Artifacts.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Collection acquired by GWU upon merger with Mount Vernon College. Collection transferred to Foggy Bottom campus in 2009.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Women -- Education; Women's colleges; Hensley, Adelia Gates; Somers, Elizabeth J.; Cole, Jean Dean
- Images, circa 1917-1925; 1920; Series 1; 4.5 Linear Feet
  Arrangement
  Organized into two subseries: Lantern Slides of Nebraska Avenue Campus and Facilities; and Photographs of Nebraska Avenue Campus, Students, and Staff.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains photographs and glass lantern slides of the Mount Vernon Seminary and College Nebraska Avenue campus, students, and faculty. The slides, which date from 1917-1924, predominantly show exteriors and interiors of campus buildings and campus grounds. Most slides are captioned. The photographs, which date from 1917-1942, depict events, exteriors, and interiors, and also include student and faculty candids and portraits.
  - Lantern Slides of Nebraska Avenue Campus and Facilities, circa 1917-1925; 1920; Series 1 Subseries 1; 1.5 Linear Feet 5 small glass slide storage boxes
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Some slides are cracked or broken. All are delicate and should be handled carefully.
    - "1100 M Street in its 'Golden Age'", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 1, Item 1)
      Slide is cracked.
    - "1100 M Street in 1881", Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 1, Item 2)
    - "Domestic Science", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 1, Item 3)
    - Field Hockey, circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 1, Item 4)
    - "The Post Office", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 1, Item 5)
    - "Little Adelia Gates at Seven", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 1, Item 6)
    - "Basketball", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 1, Item 7)
    - "The Daily Walk", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 1, Item 8)
    - "Desk in Study Hall - A Reproduction of an Old English Grammar School and Dunce Seat", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 1, Item 9)
    - "Our First Senior House of Blessed Memory", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 1, Item 10)
    - "History in the Making Elucidated by Miss Walker" [classroom scene], circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 1, Item 11)
    - "Shelter at Tennis Courts", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 1, Item 12)
    - "In the Early Years of M.V.S. and Our Mrs. Hensley", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 1, Item 13)
    - "The Mathematical Door Guards the Academic Class Rooms" [Exterior of building with columns], circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 1, Item 14)
    - "Between Classes" [Students standing under arcade of building], circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 1, Item 15)
    - "The Agony of Senior Essays" [Students studying in library], circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 1, Item 16)
    - "The North Cloister Facing the Main Entrance", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 1, Item 17)
    - "The Proposed Chapel Which Will Cost $50,000", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 1, Item 18)
      In color. Slide is cracked.
    - "Interior View of the Vestibule Entrance" [Color rendering of chapel], circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 1, Item 19)
    - "Scene from 'Pomander Walk'", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 1, Item 20)
    - Chapel Song, Musical Score, circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 1, Item 21)
    - "Corner of North Wing and the Facade Showing Bay Window of Study Hall", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 1, Item 22)
    - Sitting room, circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 2, Item 1)
    - "The Beloved Principal of the Greater M.V.S." [Adelia Gates Hensley], circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 2, Item 2)
    - Jean Dean Cole, circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 2, Item 3)
    - Dining Room, circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 2, Item 4)
    - "The Expansive Door Opposite Leads into the Dining Room", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 2, Item 5)
    - "Doorway to Refectory on South Wing", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 2, Item 6)
    - "The Great Hall", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 2, Item 7)
    - "View of the Student's Room", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 2, Item 8)
    - "Another view of the North wing showing first, door to gymnasium, second, the senior balcony, and third, the wall and door facing the chapel", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 2, Item 9)
    - "A corner of study hall", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 2, Item 10)
    - "Le Pantheon", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 2, Item 11)
    - "Le Pantheon (Skeleton)", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 2, Item 12)
    - "The Central hall. The corridor leads to the south wing and the 'Great Hall.' A corresponding corridor leads to study hall to the North. With back to the front door one faces the main staircase and the quadrangle.", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 2, Item 13)
    - "The Morning Room", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 2, Item 14)
    - "When we don cap and gown" [graduation procession], circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 2, Item 15)
      Slide is missing one pane of glass.
    - "Chapel Song", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 2, Item 16)
    - "Door facing the proposed chapel", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 2, Item 17)
    - "Returning from the 'shelter.'" [students walking down a path], circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 2, Item 18)
    - "When bustles were 'all the rage.'" [Portrait of Elizabeth J. Somers], circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 2, Item 19)
    - "Fireplace in Mrs. Hensley's Office", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 2, Item 20)
    - "Magazine and fiction library", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 2, Item 21)
    - Exteriors of campus buildings, circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 2, Item 22)
    - "The chancel" [Color architectural plan of Elizabeth Somers Chapel], circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 3, Item 1)
    - "The dining room", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 3, Item 2)
    - "North wing showing rounded arch in rear that leads to North cloister.", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 3, Item 3)
    - "Mrs. Adelia Gates Hensley", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 3, Item 4)
    - "Central Entrance Hall", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 3, Item 5)
    - "A reception room", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1
    - "Tennis Courts", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 3, Item 7)
    - Archery, circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 3, Item 8)
    - Interior of chapel, circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 3, Item 9)
    - "Outside door to gymnasium", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 3, Item 10)
    - "Senior balcony and proposed sunken garden", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 3, Item 11)
    - "The pleasant walk to the 'shelter'", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 3, Item 12)
    - "Main stairway", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 3, Item 13)
    - "A second view of the music room", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 3, Item 14)
    - "The hospitable front hall." [Exterior of building], circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 3, Item 15)
    - Interior, foyer and hallway, circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 3, Item 16)
    - Sitting room interior, circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 3, Item 17)
    - Dining room interior, circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 3, Item 18)
    - Chapel interior, circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 3, Item 19)
    - "The South and North wings with the quadrangle showing in between." [Students and dog in foreground], circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 3, Item 20)
    - Foyer with staircase, circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 3, Item 21)
    - Sitting room, circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 3, Item 22)
    - "The Foyer", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 4, Item 1)
    - "Cloister Hall", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 4, Item 2)
    - "The Quadrangle Portico in detail", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 4, Item 3)
    - Interior, office with desk, circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 4, Item 4)
    - "Study Hall", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 4, Item 5)
    - "The Music Room", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 4, Item 6)
    - "Facing south wing from north cloister", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 4, Item 7)
    - "Who says our school daisies do not thrive." [Field of daisies and stand of trees], circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 4, Item 8)
    - Exterior, Elizabeth Somers Memorial Chapel, circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 4, Item 9)
    - "The rear view, the quadrangle and the cloisters", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 4, Folder 10)
    - "The drawing room", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 4, Item 11)
    - Entryway to brick building, with staircase and flowering bushes, circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 4, Folder 12)
    - "The north cloister looking over the quadrangle to the cathedral", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 4, Item 13)
    - Sitting room, circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 4, Item 14)
    - Sitting room with fireplace, circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 4, Item 15)
    - "The memorial gate", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 4, Item 16)
    - "Then we graduated into the greater M.V.S. in 1917-1918." [Exterior of refectory], circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 4, Item 17)
    - "Mrs. Hensley's New House Gatesley", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 4, Item 18)
    - "The Swimming Pool", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 4, Item 19)
    - Mount Vernon Seminary, 204 F Street, woodblock print, circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 4, Item 20)
    - "Riding class", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 4, Item 21)
    - Nebraska Avenue campus buildings, circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Exterior view of the refectory, circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 5, Item 1)
    - "Picture after landscape gardening transforms it." [Exterior of Refectory], circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 5, Item 2)
      Slide is cracked, and glass is missing in upper left corner.
    - "Two old friends." [Two African-American men in uniform, standing in front of building], circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 5, Item 3)
    - "A faithful servitor" [African-American woman in uniform dusting chair in cloister]., circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 5, Item 4)
    - "M.V.S. Old and New and the Elizabeth Somers Chapel." [words only, no image], circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 5, Item 5)
    - "Elizabeth J. Somers Portrait by Irving Wiles", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 5, Item 6)
    - Emerson quotation: "The history of an institution is the lengthened shadow of some great personality.", circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 5, Item 7)
    - "The 'Great Personality' whom we wish to honor." [Elizabeth J. Somers standing in doorway], circa 1917-1925; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 5, Item 8)
  - Photographs of Nebraska Avenue Campus, Students, and Staff, 1884-1942; Series 1 Subseries 2; 3 Linear Feet
    - Student photos, 1884-1909; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Photographs taken by Dorothy Menefee Buxton (MVS 1912-14) including 1912 inauguration of President Wilson, 1912-17; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      General
      These photographs were formerly part of a scrapbook. They have been removed from the scrapbook and placed in folders between sheets of paper.
    - Class of 1914, Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Faculty and staff photos, 1925-30; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Campus photos, 1917-42; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Photographs, 1927-1958; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Junior class, 1930; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Basketball, 1915-1916; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Commencement and special events, 1927-1941; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Photographs of students in class, 1917-1938; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Athletics, 1934-1938; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Christmas photographs, 1938; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Daisy chain procession, 1930-1941; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Portraits of students, 1937-1939; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Three MVS bus drivers, 1940; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Founders Day, 1940; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Student activities and clubs, 1920-1934; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Three portraits in a leather frame, 1926; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Mount Vernon promotional booklets, 1930-1939; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Negatives of students, 1941; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Group photos of students, undated; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Student candids, 1922; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Photographs of Gatesly, Hensley's home, undated; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Photographs of class trees, 1916-1938; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Campus exterior color transparencies, undated; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Photographs of campus, 1929-1938; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Album of photographs of class trees, 1916-1931; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Photographs and drawings of campus interiors, undated; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Campus exterior photographs, 1938; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Athletics, undated; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Campus exteriors, 1918-1938; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Campus exterior photographs and postcards, 1917-1942; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Elizabeth Somers Chapel, exterior photos, 1925; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Elizabeth Somers Chapel, interior photos, 1938; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Centenary Celebration photos and negative, 1937; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Athletics photos, 1929; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Athletics photos, 1931-1940; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Athletics photos, 1940; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Nebraska Avenue campus photo, 1917; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Interior and exterior photos, 1920-1929; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Interior and exterior photos, 1938; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Interior and exterior photos, 1940; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Golden Jubilee photographs, 1925; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Golden Jubilee photographs, 1925; Series 1 subseries 2 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Jean Dean Cole, 1923-1938; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Anne Seymour Ames, 1884-1958; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Applewhite sisters, 1939; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Mary Louise Allen '19 photo album, 1917-1919; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 25, Folder 6)
- Scrapbooks, 1923-1942; Series 2; 3 Linear Feet
  This series contains scrapbooks of clippings mentioning Mount Vernon College and Seminary, as well as items and photographs from scrapbooks created by alumnae Florence Weaver Birch, Jean Syminton, Helen P. Andrus, Lillie Bowen Fairfax, and Marjorie Fitch Baker during their time as students at MVS. Scrapbooks date from 1923 to 1942.
  Arranged as found.
  - Scrapbook of press clippings, 1941-1942; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Household rules printed on large signs, 1940; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - MVC Publicity Book, newspaper clippings, 1939-1940; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Helen P. Andrus photo album part 1, 1927-1929; Series 2 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Helen P. Andrus photo album part 2, 1927-1929; Series 2 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Helen P. Andrus photo album part 3, 1927-1929; Series 2 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Helen P. Andrus photo album part 4, 1927-1929; Series 2 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Helen P. Andrus photo album front and back covers, 1927-1929; Series 2 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Florence Weaver Birch scrapbook, 1923-1926; Series 2 (Box 7, Scrapbook 1)
  - Florence Weaver Birch scrapbook items, 1923-1926; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Florence Weaver Birch scrapbook items, 1923-1926; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Florence Weaver Birch scrapbook items, 1923-1926; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Florence Weaver Birch scrapbook items, 1923-1926; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Jean Syminton scrapbook, 1928-1929; Series 2 (Box 13)
  - Jean Syminton scrapbook, 1928-1929; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Jean Syminton scrapbook, 1928-1929; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Mount Vernon Seminary scrapbook, 1925-1941; Series 2 (Box 9, Scrapbook 1)
  - Alumna files, Lillie Bowen Fairfax, 1938-1941; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Marjorie Fitch Baker, 1935; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Golden Jubilee guest book, 1925; Series 2 (Box 19)
  - Programs and pamphlets from Golden Jubilee scrapbook, 1925; Series 2 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Programs and pamphlets from Golden Jubilee scrapbook, 1925; Series 2 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Senior President's Book for senior class, 1926-1928; Series 2 (Box 25, Folder 8)
- Ephemera and documents, 1925-1941; Series 3; 2.5 Linear Feet
  This series contains programs for commencements, plays, recitals, and menus from Mount Vernon College and Seminary from 1925 to 1941, as well as correspondence documenting preparations for the Golden Jubilee, the Centenary Celebration, and the creation of the Elizabeth Somers Chapel.
  - Programs (including commencement, plays, and recitals), 1925-1941; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Programs (including commencement, plays, and recitals), 1928-1937; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Somers clippings, 1937; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Madrillon Lunch at the Mayan Room (menu), 1928; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Alumnae Association's Constitution and By-Laws, 1933-1938; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Award at the Chevron, 1925-1926; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Broadside -- A Creative Writing Publication, 1928-1934; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - By-Laws of Mount Vernon Seminary, 1933; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Certificate of Incorporation, 1933; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Class of 1920 -- 50th anniversary reunion, 1929-1970; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Class of 1930 -- Memorabilia, 1929-1960; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Class of 1930 -- Memorabilia and reunion photos, 1929-1966; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Class of 1940 -- "The Sporty Forty" Publication on the 25th Reunion of the Class of 1940, 1965; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Class Song, Founders' Day Song, Senior Class Song, 1920-1940; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - The Creed of Mount Vernon Seminary (5 copies), 1919; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Endowment Fund papers, 1934-1937; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 12)